<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://cdn.rawgit.com/selite/selite/master/extension-sequencer/src/chrome/content/selenese_reference_to_html.xsl"?>
<!-- If you'd like to preview this reference.xml in Firefox, open it either
- online at https://cdn.rawgit.com/SeLite/SelBlocksGlobal/master/sel-blocks-fx_xpi/chrome/content/reference.xml, or
- offline at chrome://selite-extension-sequencer/content/selenese_reference.html?chrome://selite-selblocks-global/content/reference.xml
Xml-stylesheet (whether remote or even local) didn't load up work when you open this in a browser locally via file://
-->
<apidoc package-name="SelBlocks Global">
<function name="label">
    <comment>Declares a label for 'goto' command.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="skipNext">
    <param name="amount">Number of commands to skip. Default 1.</param>
    <comment>Skip one or several next commands, as given in parameter <code>amount</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="goto">
    <param name="label">Name of a label to go to</param>
    <comment>Go to the position at the given label.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="gotoIf">
    <param name="condExpr">Condition expression. If it evaluates to true (compared non-strictly),
        then the control goes to a statement at the given label.
    </param>
    <param name="label">Name of a label to go to</param>
    <comment>Go to the position at the given label, if condExpr evaluates to true (compared non-strictly).
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="if">
    <param name="condExpr">Condition expression. It determines whether to run
        the positive branch or negative branch (if present).
    </param>
    <comment>Conditional statement and a start of its positive branch.
        It evaluates given <code>condExpr</code>.
        If it evaluates to true (compared non-strictly), then the control flow continues
        until the matching <code>endIf</code> or matching <code>else</code> (or <code>elseIf</code>). Otherwise,
        any <code>elseIf</code> steps are considered. If none of them has condition that is true and if there is a matching <code>else</code> statement, then the control continues from there
        (the negative branch). Otherwise it continues from the matching <code>endIf</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="ifPromise">
    <param name="condExpr">A Javascript expression that evaluates to a <code>Promise</code>. Its result (once resolved) determines whether to run
        the positive branch or negative branch (if present).
    </param>
    <comment>Similar to <code>if</code>, but <code>condExpr</code> should evaluate to a <code>Promise</code> object. The resolved value of the promise determines the control flow.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="elseIf">
    <param name="condExpr">Condition expression. It determines whether to run
        the positive branch or negative branch (if present).
    </param>
    <comment>Conditional sub-statement and a start of its positive branch.
      It can be used only after an <code>if</code> (or after any previous <code>elseIf</code> step(s)). It must be located before <code>endIf</code> of the matching <code>if</code>.
        If the matching <code>if</code> had a false condition (and if any and all <code>elseIf</code> steps had false condition(s)), then this <code>elseIf</code> evaluates its <code>condExpr</code>.
        If that is true (compared non-strictly), then the control flow continues
        until the matching <code>endIf</code> or matching <code>else</code> (or until next <code>elseIf</code>). Otherwise,
        if there is a matching <code>else</code> statement, then the control continues from there
        (the negative branch). Otherwise it continues from the matching <code>endIf</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="elseIfPromise">
    <param name="condExpr">A Javascript expression that evaluates to a <code>Promise</code>. Its result (once resolved) determines whether to run
        the positive branch or negative branch (if present).
    </param>
    <comment>Similar to <code>elseIf</code>, but <code>condExpr</code> should evaluate to a <code>Promise</code> object. The resolved value of the promise determines the control flow.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="else">
    <comment>Negative branch of a matching <code>if</code> statement; optional. If the matching <code>if</code>
        evaluated its condition as false (compared non-strictly), then it passes the control here.
        <br/>If the condition evaluated as true (compared non-strictly), then the positive branch was
        processed (i.e. any statements between the matching <code>if</code> and this <code>else</code>).
        On reaching this <code>else</code>, the control skips this negative branch and continues from the
        matching <code>endIf</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="elsePromise">
    <comment>Similar to <code>else</code>, but for use with <code>ifPromise</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="endIf">
    <comment>End of conditional statement. After evaluating the condition of the matching <code>if</code>
        and after running its positive (<code>if</code>) branch or its negative branch
        (<code>else</code>, if present), the control switches here. <code>endIf</code> ends the whole
        <code>if</code> (and optional <code>else</code>) structure. It ends the negative
        branch (<code>else</code>, if present), otherwise it ends the positive branch (<code>if</code>).
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="endIfPromise">
    <comment>Similar to <code>endIf</code>, but for use with <code>ifPromise</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="while">
    <param name="condExpr">Condition expression.
    </param>
    <comment>Conditional loop statement. As far as it evaluates to true (compared non-strictly),
        it keeps running all statements up to the matching <code>endWhile</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="whilePromise">
    <param name="condExpr">A Javascript expression that evaluates to a <code>Promise</code>. Its result (once resolved) determines whether to start/continue with the loop, or whether to skip/finish it.
    </param>
    <comment>Conditional Promise-based loop statement. It evaluates <code>condExpr</code>, which should return a <code>Promise</code> object. As far as the promise resolves to true (compared non-strictly), it keeps running all statements up to the matching <code>endWhilePromise</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="endWhile">
    <comment>End of the matching <code>while</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="endWhilePromise">
    <comment>End of the matching <code>whilePromise</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="repeat">
    <comment>Conditional loop statement with a condition at the end. It repeats all statements up to the matching <code>until</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="until">
    <param name="negativeCondExpr">Negative condition expression.
    </param>
    <comment>End of the matching <code>repeat</code>. It keeps repeating all statements since the matching <code>repeat</code> until condition <code>negativeCondExpr</code> evaluates to true (compared non-strictly).
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="repeatPromise">
    <comment>Conditional Promise-based loop statement with a condition at the end. It repeats all statements up to the matching <code>untilPromise</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="untilPromise">
    <param name="negativeCondExpr">A Javascript expression that evaluates to a <code>Promise</code>. Its result (once resolved) determines whether to stop the loop, or whether to continue it.
    </param>
    <comment>End of the matching <code>repeatPromise</code>. It evaluates <code>negativeCondExpr</code>, which should return a <code>Promise</code> object. Once the promise resolves to <code>true</code> (compared non-strictly), the loop stops running all statements since the matching <code>repeatPromise</code>. As far as it resolves to <code>false</code>, the loop continues. However, if the promise fails (rather than resolves), this raises a catcheable error.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="for">
    <param name="forSpec">Composite defining loop bounds and repetition condition,
        C/C++/Java/Javascript/PHP-like,
        in 3 parts separated by semicolons: <code>initiation; condition; iteration</code>.
        For example: <code>$i=0; $i&lt;=100; $i++</code>
    </param>
    <comment>Loop with initiation, condition for repetition and iteration.
        First, it evaluates the initiation part of parameter <code>forSpec</code>.
        Then it evaluates the condition part of <code>forSpec</code>. If true (compared non-strictly), it runs any
        statement(s) between this <code>for</code> and its matching <code>endFor</code>.
        On reaching the matching <code>endFor</code>, it evaluates iteration part of <code>forSpec</code>.
        Then it evaluates the condition part again and if true, it repeats the statements again...
        When the condition part evaluates to false (compared non-strictly), it passes the control
        to the matching <code>endFor</code> statement.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="endFor">
    <comment>End of <code>for</code> loop.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="forEach">
    <param name="varName">Variable name, that will be assigned values from <code>valueExpr</code>.</param>
    <param name="valueExpr">Comma-separated values or expressions, that will be iterated through. Can be empty.</param>
    <comment>It iterates through given list of values/expressions, assigning each
        to a stored variable with name <code>varName</code>. For each value, it then runs statement(s)
        up to the matching <code>endForeach</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="endForEach">
    <comment>End of the matching <code>forEach</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="foreach">
    <comment>Obsolete. Instead, use <code>forEach</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="endForeach">
    <comment>Obsolete. Instead, use <code>endForEach</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="forIterator">
    <param name="varName">Variable name, that will be assigned values from <code>valueExpr</code>.</param>
    <param name="iteratorExpr">A Javascript expression that evaluates to an iterator object (not iterable, neither GeneratorFunction).</param>
    <comment>It iterates the given iterator. It stores each iterated value to a stored variable with name <code>varName</code>. For each value, it then runs statement(s) up to the matching <code>endForeach</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="endForIterator">
    <comment>End of the matching <code>forIterator</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="forIterable">
    <param name="varName">Variable name, that will be assigned values from <code>valueExpr</code>.</param>
    <param name="iteratorExpr">A Javascript expression that evaluates to an iterable object (not an iterator, neither GeneratorFunction).</param>
    <comment>It iterates the given iterable. It stores each iterated value to a stored variable with name <code>varName</code>. For each value, it then runs statement(s) up to the matching <code>endForeach</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="endForIterable">
    <comment>End of the matching <code>forIterable</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="loadVars">
    <comment>Deprecated. Use <code>loadXmlVars</code> instead.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="loadXmlVars">
    <param name="xmlfile">File path or a file:// URI to an xml file to load. If it's not a file:// URL, then it should be relative to location of the test case (not the test suite). Value sets is loaded from &lt;vars&gt; element(s).</param>
    <param name="selector">Boolean condition to select a set of values from the XML. Optional; if not present,
        then the XML must have exactly one set of variables - one element &lt;vars&gt;.
    </param>
    <comment>
        Load a set of variable(s) from an XML. If condition is present, then
        <code>loadVars</code> keeps reading sets of values from XML, until the condition evaluates
        to true (compared non-strictly). If it reaches the end of XML and the condition is still false,
        <code>loadVars</code> fails. Each set of variable(s) is within its &lt;vars&gt; element.
        See original reference at <a href="http://refactoror.wikia.com/wiki/Selblocks_Reference">http://refactoror.wikia.com/wiki/Selblocks_Reference</a> for more.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="loadJsonVars">
    <comment>Similar to loadXmlVars, but this is for JSON. See loadXmlVars.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="forXml">
    <param name="xmlpath">File path or a file:// URL to an XML file. You can enter path to the file, relative to location of the current test case (not the test suite). (You can use Windows or Unix folder separators \ or /). In order to pass a full absolute path, enter file://...</param>
    <comment>An XML-based loop. (I think that) on each iteration, it loads a set of variables from the XML
    (one set of variables per one element &lt;vars&gt;). Then it runs any statement(s) up to the matching <code>endForXml</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="endForXml">
    <comment>End of the matching <code>forXml</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="forJson">
    <param name="jsonpath">File path or a file:// URL to a JSON file. You can enter path to the file, relative to location of the current test case (not the test suite). (You can use Windows or Unix folder separators \ or /). In order to pass a full absolute path, enter file://...</param>
    <comment>This doesn't work well and I believe it didn't work well in original SelBlocks either. Developers: see @TODO in selblocks.js. Doc. once fixed: A JSON-based loop. (I think that) on each iteration, it loads a set of variables from the given file which should contain them in JSON notation. Then it runs any statement(s) up to the matching <code>endForXml</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="endForJson">
    <comment>End of the matching <code>forJson</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="continue">
  <comment>Jump back to top of the current (innermost active) loop (either <code>for</code>, <code>foreach</code>, <code>while</code>, <code>forJson</code> or <code>forXml</code>) for next iteration, if any.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
  </comment>
</function>
<function name="break">
    <comment>Jump back to the bottom of the current (innermost active) loop and exit it.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="call">
    <param name="srcName">Name of the script to call.</param>
    <param name="argSpec">Argument(s) passed to the called script, optional. Each argument becomes a stored Selenese variable in that function. Use following two ways:
        <ol>
            <li>Comma-separated assignments in form <code>variableName=expression</code>. You can use <code>$upperStoredVariableName</code> to access stored variables in <code>expression</code>.</li>
            <li>Alternatively, pass an object passed <code>=&lt;&gt;...&lt;&gt;</code> as per https://selite.github.io/EnhancedSelenese. Each field of that object is passed to the Selenese function. (However, do not use <code>@&lt;&gt;...&lt;&gt;</code> syntax.)</li>
        </ol>
    </param>
    <comment>Call a script with the given name. Just like calling a function/method in common
        programming languages. It
        <ol>
            <li>saves any stored variables, and it removes them from the current scope</li>
            <li>puts all given arguments to the current scope of stored variables</li>
            <li>passes control to the called <code>script</code></li>
        </ol>
        The called script may be in a different test case, as far as it's a part of the same test suite (this
        is how SelBlocks Global differs from SelBlocks). If the called script finishes
        correctly - either at its <code>endScript</code> or <code>return</code> (if present) - then
        <ol>
            <li>the control is passed back to the caller</li>
            <li>any stored variables from the called script are lost</li>
            <li>the original stored variables are loaded to the scope</li>
            <li>any returned result from the called script is avaliable in stored variable <code>_result</code></li>
        </ol>
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="function">
    <comment>Start of a script, which is a callable block, like a function/method in common programming languages.
        It gets invoked via <code>call</code> statement. It can (optionally) receive parameter(s)
        and it can (optionally) return a value via <code>return</code>.
        It has a separate scope of stored variables. It contains statement(s) up to the nearest <code>endScript</code>.
        It can call other scripts via <code>call</code>, but it cannot contain other scripts within itself.
        It can call itself recursively, either directly or indirectly.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
    <param name="funcName">
        Name of the function.
    </param>
</function>
<function name="script">
    <comment>Obsolete. Use <code>function</code> instead.</comment>
</function>
<function name="endScript">
    <comment>Obsolete. Use <code>endFunction</code> instead.</comment>
</function>
<function name="return">
    <param name="value">Value/expression to evaluate and return.</param>
    <comment>It ends the currently executed <code>function</code>, returning the
        flow control to the caller and passing given value as stored variable <code>_result</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="endFunction">
    <comment>It ends the currently executed <code>function</code>, returning the
        flow control to the caller, without setting stored variable <code>_result</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="exitTest">
    <comment>It ends the current test run.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="try">
    <param name="tryName">Label-like name of this try block, used for validation of proper pairing; optional.</param>
    <comment>
        It starts a <code>try..catch..finally..endTry</code> block. If there is any exception/error within this block, then any subsequent steps are skipped and it runs the <code>catch</code> part (optional). If there's a <code>finally</code> part, that gets executed whether the <code>try</code> part was successful or not.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="catch">
    <param name="errorTextOrRegExp">Error message to catch, optional. If present, it must be a Javascript expression that evaluates to a string or to a regular expression, matching the whole error message or its substring. E.g. a string quoted within '..' or "..." , or a regular expression within /.../.</param>
    <comment>
        It starts a <code>catch</code> part of its <code>try..catch..finally..endTry</code> block. If there was a matching exception, then its steps are run (until <code>finally</code> or until its matching <code>endTry</code>). There can be only one or no <code>catch</code> for any <code>try</code>.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="finally">
    <comment>
        It starts a <code>finally</code> part of its <code>try..catch..finally..endTry</code> block. Steps between <code>finally</code> and its ending <code>endTry</code> are executed, whether there was any error/exception or not (unless the testing stopped for some other reason, e.g. <code>exitTest</code>).
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="endTry">
    <param name="tryName">Label-like name of this try block, used for validation of proper pairing; optional.</param>
    <comment>End of <code>try..catch..finally..endTry</code> block.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="throw">
    <param name="error">A Javascript expression that yields a string or an error. If it's a string literal, enclose it in apostrophes or quotes.</param>
    <comment>Throw an error.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="promise">
    <param name="script">A Javascript expression that evaluates to a <code>Promise</code>.</param>
    <comment>
        Similar to <code>getEval</code>, but <code>Promise</code>-based. It evaluates the given script just like <code>getEval</code> does. However, it requires the result of the script to be a <code>Promise</code> object. Then it waits until the promise gets resolved, or until it times out. If the promise times out or it resolves with a failure, this throws an exception.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="storePromiseValue">
    <param name="script">A Javascript expression that evaluates to a <code>Promise</code>.</param>
    <param name="variableName">Name of a stored variable to save the result value of the promise, if the promise gets resolved successfully.</param>
    <comment>
        Similar to <code>promise</code>. If the promise resolves successfully, this command saves the result to the given stored variable.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
<function name="breakPoint">
    <comment>
        Stop execution here as if it were a breakpoint. It allows the user to resume execution via Selenium IDE GUI.
        <br/>Use for debugging only. Don't use when running all suites with Run All Favorites.
        <br/>
        This command is a part of SeLite SelBlocks Global.
    </comment>
</function>
</apidoc>